all right so we we have a question here
that actually leads into a big segment
of the beginner boost um related to
being an autodidact you know being a
person in control of their learning not
just an independent learner but somebody
who takes active steps to make a
strategy about what they need to learn
and document the learning process and
the question specifically is what is a
good strategy for documenting the
learning process
uh I was thinking about gitbook or
textual diagrams and Theory using
YouTube to demonstrate tutorials how to
exercise the social linking marking and
the answer is yes to all of that um I
think the very first thing to say here
is that the process of documenting your
learning is highly personal and this is
one of those reasons that I believe
one-on-one mentoring or mentoring um
between individuals so important because
everyone is different we all have
multiple intelligences we have different
learning styles we have different
learning types we have different um
handicaps some of us can type fast some
of us can't some of us want to be able
to access our learning materials from a
phone some of us want to be able to just
sit in front of a terminal all day
everybody's different so before I answer
further in this particular question I
just want to be clear that I'm going to
be sharing my personal ideas about this
and then you can take those and you can
decide if that works for you um there's
going to be several videos on this
particular question um so I'm going to
use this question as kind of the the
high-end overview of of the answer um
and and quite frankly the answer that I
think you should do is create a GitHub
account number one and to create a notes
repo which is in another that creating a
GitHub account creating a notes repo
already has a video if you can't find it
go to skill stack. and find the link and
click on that that is already how I
think you should start right and what
you put in your the we talk about how
you can go into the GitHub and you can
actually edit you can type in there you
can use that as your place to save
things you can even do that from your
phone so that is an absolute you already
need a GitHub account because you need I
mean every technologist on the planet
needs a GI up account the end I'm not
going to debate that with anybody if you
want to argue that with me fine the rest
of the world has decided that that is
where source code goes and that is where
it's better it's more important than
LinkedIn also a topic for another
video so start there put your notes in
there and start writing what I call a
codebook now um a code book is the
concept of
writing notes but also having little
segments of runnable code that are also
contained in the GitHub repo and we're
not going to be doing it right away but
as we go through this beginner boost we
are regularly going to be adding
runnable code to our code books and what
that means is you can take notes you
know you can write a little bit of
markdown you don't have to you haven't
learned markdown yet so there's a
question about that we'll get to that in
a sec but you're just taking notes
that's all you really need to know
you're taking notes and then you're also
writing runnable code in the same GitHub
repo right and at first the reason that
I have you do you know get a GitHub now
and just start taking notes about these
videos about how to get a job and that
kind of thing and what your thoughts are
on that and you're linking to different
resources that you think are valuable
you're already kind of taking advantage
of that and so this this notes repo is
the beginning of your knowledge base and
so that is the
fundamental question here and I don't
like starting with the term knowledge
base because you know it's a big ass
term knowledge base is just a thing
where you put all your notes but the
thing that makes it into a knowledge
base is it's now queriable you can now
search it and one of the primary reasons
for having GitHub right away is because
every single GitHub repo already has a
built-in search engine through GitHub
and I'm not going to show it to you
right now but just know it's there
anything you save to a GitHub repo can
be searched by keyword just by using the
GitHub interface so yes we are going to
talk about lots of other crazy cool ways
to to manage your knowledge such as
zedcast then including you know the
popular tools like obsidian versus
markdown and all the different ways to
write your data and and write your your
code base but the fundamental part of
all of that the foundation of all of
that is putting it on GitHub so you can
start with that now you can get a GI up
account you can create a notes repo if
you want to change the name later to zet
like I have done or any of these other
things and by the way creating a tool to
query your database is a really great
project to flex your coding muscles
particularly your go programming muscles
if you want to be able to do that kind
of thing um so those are those are all
topics that will come later so the
answer is you do you but do it on GitHub
and do it in a repo that is going to get
you started properly and that includes
linking to tutorials and everything and
eventually it will include being able to
run code from your knowledge base all
right